http://www.typing-lessons.org/privacy.html

×
Principles for Effective Learning
No mistakes. Always be sure and in control.
Follow the principle of 100% correct practice: to make a mistake is to learn incorrect things, and to confuse that which you already know.Slower is faster. Speed comes from certainty.
The more you type things correctly, no matter how slow it has to be, the more certain you will be, and the faster you will become a proficient typist.
Increase speed only when you feel sure enough to do so.Don't look at the keyboard! If you don't know where a key is, look at the keyboard to find it, then look away and type the key.
Do not guess; always be sure.Type to a steady rhythm. Generally, the time between keystrokes should be the same, giving you a sense of flow and the ability to scan ahead at a constant speed.Relax. No unnecessary or dysfunctional tension. Enjoy the rhythm of your own typing!Hit the keys squarely in the center. If you find you aren't consistently doing so, SLOW DOWN!!! It should feel good to type!
Close
×
Instructions for Use
Press the "Click here to start" button, then type what you see on the screen.
If you type correctly, the letter will turn to grey.
If you err, it won't, and you will hear an error sound.To do the same again (which you should do if you make ANY mistakes), press the "Go again!" button that appears when you finish.Remember, shoot for no errors!!
That is the most important thing right now. Speed means nothing; certainty and correctness are what's important.For practical purposes, you can consider yourself having mastered an exercise only if you are able to type three reloaded screens of exercises in a row in under 60 seconds each, with no errors, confidently.
Close
×
Technical Help
If you are accessing this course on the desktop or a laptop, Google Chrome (currently the most popular browser in the world) is the recommended browser for this site, and switching to it will likely solve any issues you may be experiencing.
It is a free download, easy to install, and available for all platforms.
Other major browsers, such as Apple Safari, Mozilla Firefox and Microsoft Internet Explorer should generally be ok, however please make sure you are using a current version.
Older versions or other browsers may give inconsistent results.
Javascript is required for the typing functionality, so please ensure it is turned on in your browser preferences.
Some third-party extensions for web browsers, such as ad blockers, might interefere with the typing functionality.
If you are using such an extension, turn it off temporarily and see if that is the cause.
If so, it should be possible to whitelist this site so that the extension is turned off for this site only.
This course is not designed to be used with a soft keyboard on a tablet, although it has been successfully tested to work with iOS devices (iPad and iPhone).
If you are on Android or a Windows Mobile device it is hit or miss, however it should work absolutely fine with an external keyboard.
It is highly recommended to learn touch typing on a physical keyboard for the tactile feedback, and bluetooth keyboards can be obtained very inexpensively these days (i.e. as little as $10).
This is a VERY worthwhile investment to learn touch typing, a skill which will last you a lifetime.
If you're still having problems, you can still access the old, Flash-based version of the course here.
Close
Peter's Online Typing Course
Preliminaries
Introduction and Overview
Principles for Effective Learning
Typing Ergonomics
Which Fingers Go Where
Typing Lessons
Row by Row: Top & Home Rows Combined
Bottom Row Right: NM,./?
Bottom Row Left: ZXCVB
Putting It All Together: Bottom Row
Letters Consolidation
Take a Break!
The Brackets
Numbers Row Left: 12345
Numbers Row Right: 67890
Putting It All Together: Numbers
Numbers Row Left + Shift: !@#$%
Numbers Row Right + Shift: ^&*()
Math Keys: -=_+
Programming Keys: ~`|\
Putting It All Together: Special Characters
Numbers Row + Special Characters
The Last Connection
The Backspace/Delete Key
Final Exam
Graduation
The Big Zig
Do You Have My Number?
Math Key Pinky Buster
Speed Typing: The Most Common Words
The Shift Key Shuffle
Make Your Own Exercise!
Typing Practice
Business Typing
Computer Programming Typing
English Typing
Fairy Tales Typing
Fun Typing
Geography Typing
Legal Typing
Peter's Online Typing Course
Share me! Share on FacebookTweetShare on Google+Pin itSend email
Preliminaries
Introduction and Overview
Principles for Effective Learning
Typing Ergonomics
Which Fingers Go Where
Typing Lessons
Home Row, Left Hand
Home Row, Right Hand
Row by Row: Top & Home Rows Combined
Bottom Row Right: NM,./?
Bottom Row Left: ZXCVB
Putting It All Together: Bottom Row
Letters Consolidation
Take a Break!
The Brackets
Numbers Row Left: 12345
Numbers Row Right: 67890
Putting It All Together: Numbers
Numbers Row Left + Shift: !@#$%
Numbers Row Right + Shift: ^&*()
Math Keys: -=_+
Programming Keys: ~`|\
Putting It All Together: Special Characters
Numbers Row + Special Characters
The Last Connection
The Backspace/Delete Key
Final Exam
Graduation
The Big Zig
Do You Have My Number?
Math Key Pinky Buster
Speed Typing: The Most Common Words
The Shift Key Shuffle
Make Your Own Exercise!
Typing Practice
Business Typing
Computer Programming Typing
English Typing
Fairy Tales Typing
Fun Typing
Geography Typing
Legal Typing
Privacy Policy
This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally identifiable information' (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.
What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website?
We do not collect any personal information from visitors of our site, such as names, email addresses or credit card numbers.
Log Data
When you use our visit our website, our web server automatically provides us with a log displaying general visitor information, such the user IP address, browser type, operating system, the referring web page, pages visited within this site, location, mobile carrier, device information, search terms, and cookie information.
How do we use log data?
We use log data only on an aggregate basis, for the purpose of improving our site.
This information is not shared with any other party.
How do we protect visitor information?
We only provide articles and information and media. We never ask for personal or private information like names, email addresses or credit card numbers.
Do we use 'cookies'?
This site uses cookies indirectly through the use of Google Analytics.
In addition, our third-party advertisers may also make use of cookies. Please see below for more information.
Third-party disclosure
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information.
Third-party links
Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.
Google
Google's advertising requirements are described by Google's Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en
We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.
Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.
We have implemented the following:
Remarketing with Google AdSense
Google Display Network Impression Reporting
Demographics and Interests Reporting
DoubleClick Platform Integration
Third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.
Opting out:
Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.
COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)
When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online.
We do not specifically market to children under 13.
© 2004-2020 Peter Hudson.
All rights reserved.   This page last updated: 11 December 2020   |
Privacy Policy
